All right, back to the lab.
よし､ ラボに戻ろう｡
Back to our project.
話をプロジェクトに戻そう｡
Time to work with tools.
道具を使う時間だ｡
I am in the week two folder in JupyterLab, and I'm launching day four.
僕は今､ JupyterLabの2週目のフォルダにいて､ 4日目に突入するところだ｡
It's time for us to bring together what we've done so far to make a customer service assistant for a
これまでやってきたことを結集して､ 架空の航空会社のカスタマーサービス・アシスタントを作る時が来た｡
We start with some imports.
まずは輸入品から｡
As usual, we initialize a load of key.
いつものように､ キーのロードを初期化する｡
We're going to use GPT four mini today, and the OpenAI initialization is there.
今日はGPT four miniを使うつもりで､ OpenAIの初期化はそこにある｡
The system message.
システムメッセージ｡
You're a helpful assistant for an airline called flight I, flight II flight A, however you want to
あなたはI便､ II便､ A便と呼ばれる航空会社のアシスタントだ｡
There it is.
あれだ｡
Give short, courteous answers no more than one sentence.
一文以内で短く丁寧に答えること｡
Always be accurate.
常に正確に｡
If you don't know the answer, say so.
答えがわからなければ､ そう言ってください｡
This, of course, a very good type of, uh, system prompt.
これはもちろん､ システム・プロンプトの非常に良いタイプだ｡
Um, if you're, uh, want to have a strong focus on lack of hallucinations on truthfulness.
ええと､ もし､ 幻覚がないことに強く焦点を当てたいのであれば､ 真実性を重視したい｡
So we run that.
だから､ それを実行するんだ｡
Then this is something you're now very familiar with.
それなら､ これはもうお馴染みのことだ｡
This is the chat function in the style that Gradio expects it.
これはGradioが期待するスタイルのチャット機能である｡
It takes a message, it takes history, and it then builds the style that is expected by OpenAI.
メッセージを受け取り､ 履歴を受け取り､ そしてOpenAIが期待するスタイルを構築する｡
You may notice this looks a bit shorter than before.
以前より少し短く見えるかもしれない｡
And that's because this time I'm not streaming back results.
そして､ 今回は結果をストリーミングで返さないからだ｡
I think we've done enough of that.
それはもう十分やったと思う｡
And since we're going with these short responses, streaming is probably overkill.
それに､ このような短い返答をするのだから､ ストリーミングはやり過ぎだろう｡
Let's see this in action.
実際に見てみよう｡
Up it comes.
上がってきた｡
We know Gradio so well now.
私たちは今､ グラディオのことをよく知っている｡
We don't need to show off about it and we can say hi there.
私たちはそれを見せびらかす必要はないし､ そこで挨拶することもできる｡
Hello, how can I assist you today?
こんにちは､ 本日はどのようなご用件でしょうか？
I want to go to London, my hometown.
故郷のロンドンに行きたい｡
I always want to go there.
私はいつもそこに行きたいと思っている｡
Great choice.
素晴らしい選択だ｡
Would you like to help finding flights to London?
ロンドン行きのフライトをお探しですか？
Yes.
そうだ｡
How much is a ticket?
チケットはいくらですか？
I don't have real time pricing, but you can check our website or app for the latest ticket prices.
リアルタイムの価格は分からないが､ 最新のチケット価格はウェブサイトやアプリで確認できる｡
London.
ロンドンだ｡
So you know it's good to see as instructed.
だから､ 指示された通りに見るのがいいんだ｡
It does not hallucinate prices.
価格を幻覚することはない｡
It doesn't try and go there.
そこに行こうとはしない｡
It does what it's told, and you can also see it's giving short one line responses just as we asked.
言われたとおりに動くし､ 私たちが頼んだように1行の短い返事をしているのもわかる｡
Okay, back we go.
よし､ 戻ろう｡
So it is time to talk about tools, an incredibly powerful feature provided by the frontier LMS.
そこで､ フロンティアLMSが提供する信じられないほど強力な機能であるツールについてお話ししましょう｡
You can write a function, have it call that function as part of its response.
関数を書いて､ レスポンスの一部としてその関数を呼び出すことができる｡
Sounds almost spooky.
ほとんど不気味な響きだ｡
We're giving it the power to run code on our machine.
私たちのマシン上でコードを実行する力を与えているのだ｡
As I said, it's just a kind of story and that will soon be very clear to you.
さっきも言ったように､ これは一種の物語に過ぎない｡
So let's start by making ourselves a function, a function that is going to be a useful function that
では､ まず自分自身で関数を作ってみよう｡ この関数は､ アラームを武装させるのに便利な関数だ｡
And that function is going to be called get ticket price given a city.
この関数は､ 都市を指定してチケット価格を取得する｡
So uh, it's going to begin by printing.
だから､ 印刷することから始まるんだ｡
Get ticket price called for destination City.
目的地の都市で呼び出されるチケット料金を入手する｡
And we're doing that so that we can watch later to see when this function is called.
そして､ この関数がいつ呼び出されるかを後で確認できるようにするためだ｡
Uh, what we do is we take the destination city and we make it lowercase.
つまり､ 目的地の都市を小文字にするんだ｡
So this works and we look it up in this dictionary where we've got lowercase cities and prices.
そこで､ 小文字の都市と価格を辞書で調べてみる｡
If it doesn't find it, it says unknown.
見つからなければ不明と表示される｡
Let's just add one in here.
ここで1つ付け加えよう｡
Why not change things on the fly?
なぜその場で変更しないのか？
Probably break everything.
おそらく､ すべてを壊してしまうだろう｡
Hopefully not.
そうでないことを祈る｡
Let's give ourselves Berlin and a nice, cheap, special deal for for flights to Berlin.
ベルリンと､ ベルリン行きの航空券のための素敵で､ 安くて､ 特別な取引をしよう｡
Why not?
なぜだ？
Um.
うーん｡
Okay, let's run that.
よし､ 実行してみよう｡
So we will now try this out.
では､ これを試してみよう｡
Get ticket price to Berlin, see what we get.
ベルリンまでのチケット代､ 何が手に入るか見てみよう｡
And it says tool, get ticket price.
そして､ ツール､ チケット代と書いてある｡
Called for Berlin for $99.
ベルリンに99ドルで電話｡
Now you might be thinking to yourself.
今､ あなたはこう思ったかもしれない｡
What does he mean, tool?
道具ってどういう意味？
This isn't a tool, it's just a function.
これはツールではなく､ 単なる機能だ｡
And the answer is for now, it's just a function.
そして答えは､ 今のところただの機能だ｡
We're about to make it into a tool.
我々はそれをツールにしようとしている｡
I don't know if you actually sound that way, but that's how you sound in my mind.
実際にそう聞こえるかどうかはわからないが､ 私の中ではそう聞こえる｡
So anyway, that that is us creating our tool.
とにかく､ これが僕らのツールを作るということなんだ｡
Now, the process of putting these tools into our interface with an LLM is a bit storied.
さて､ これらのツールをLLMとのインターフェイスに導入する過程には､ ちょっとした物語がある｡
It's not going to be as simple as bringing up a Gradio interface.
グラディオのインターフェイスを立ち上げるような単純なものにはならないだろう｡
Regrettably, uh, it's more involved.
残念ながら､ もっと複雑なんだ｡
There's good reason for that.
それには理由がある｡
And we'll find out why.
そして､ その理由を突き止める｡
Um, but it is a little bit more involved.
うーん､ でももう少し複雑なんだ｡
Um, but the good news is it's very much a sort of cookie cutter style that can be replicated for other
うーん､ でも良いニュースは､ 他のツールの他のファンクション・コールでも再現できる､ ある種のクッキー・カッターのようなスタイルだということだ｡
So you'll be able to reuse this for your own projects.
だから､ これを自分のプロジェクトに再利用することができる｡
And I very much hope you do.
そして､ そうなることを強く望んでいる｡
One of the intentions of having these useful projects in here is so that you can then take this as a
ここに有用なプロジェクトを掲載した意図のひとつは､ これをリソースとして､ 自分のプロジェクトにコードの断片を使えるようにすることだ｡
Um, and I'll certainly be recommending that you try adding your own tools.
そして､ あなた自身のツールを追加してみることをお勧めします｡
So you should be closely following this.
だから､ あなたはこれを注意深く追うべきだ｡
Uh, and the first thing I'm going to mention is that we need to build a particular dictionary structure
ええと､ 最初に言っておくのは､ 今書いた関数を記述するために必要な特定の辞書構造を構築する必要があるということだ｡
And this is what it looks like.
そして､ こんな感じだ｡
Price function, I'll call it.
プライス・ファンクションと呼ぼう｡
You call it anything you want.
好きなように呼べばいい｡
You give it a name and you describe it.
名前をつけて､ それを説明する｡
And the way you describe it is in plain Old English, because this is going to be given to the LLM so
LLMがこの関数をいつ呼び出すのが適切かを理解できるようにするためだ｡
So it says get the price of a return ticket to the destination city.
つまり､ 目的地までの往復航空券の料金を取得すると書いてある｡
Call this whenever you need to know the ticket price.
チケットの値段を知りたいときはいつでも電話してください｡
For example, when a customer asks how much is a ticket to the city?
例えば､ 客が「市内までのチケットはいくらですか？
So giving it an example is always a good, good technique.
だから､ 例を挙げることは常に良い､ 良いテクニックなんだ｡
And that's what we're using here.
それが､ ここで使っているものだ｡
And then you provide the parameters in this setup here.
そして､ このセットアップでパラメータを指定する｡
And our function has one parameter destination city.
そして､ この関数には1つのパラメータがある｡
And that is what the parameter does.
そして､ それこそがパラメーターの役割なのだ｡
So that's how you describe the function that you're using.
そうやって､ 使っている機能を説明するんだ｡
And you can see I say that it's a required parameter.
そして､ 必須パラメータだと言っているのがわかるだろう｡
So that is the setup.
これがセットアップだ｡
And at this point I'm going to pause for a moment.
そしてこの時点で､ 私は少し立ち止まるつもりだ｡
And in the next video we're going to keep going.
そして次のビデオでは､ さらに続けるつもりだ｡
And we're going to arm the LLM with this function.
そして､ LLMにこの機能を持たせるつもりだ｡
See you there.
そこで会おう